Finding Aid for Common Cause in Michigan Records 1971-1998
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Common Cause in Michigan Records
1971-1998
1973-1994
Common Cause in Michigan.
Record group consists of Administration, Office Reference, and Reforms subgroups; files relate to lobbying efforts on behalf of campaign reform, ethics in politics, lobbying reform.
90125 Bm 2
16.75 linear feet in 17 boxes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
Records were received from Karen M. Merrill, executive director of Common Cause in Michigan, in September 1989 (Donor no. 7724 ). Additions were received in June, 2003.
The record group is open for research.
Common Cause in Michigan, a citizens group committed to securing good government, was founded in 1973 The group grew out of a nationwide reform impulse spurred by citizens who felt that politicians were more responsive to special interest groups than to the common weal. The national Common Cause serves as clearinghouse for the financial operations; it distributes income from dues to the various state concerns. As the local chapter of the national organization, Common Cause in Michigan has considerable autonomy in determining the issues and tactics to adopt in its pursuit of more representative government. The Michigan group has attempted to win campaign finances disclosure laws, to reduce conflicts of interest of legislators, to constrain lobbying, to open meetings, and generally to secure ethical governance. Perhaps the most effective tactics available to Common Cause in Michigan involve the use of the media: releasing reports and statements to the press, having favorable editorials published, and making the Common Cause view public in news stories, features, and columns. The group will also directly lobby the state legislators, and indirectly lobby by stimulating letter writing campaigns through a network of activists.
Common Cause in Michigan is a self-consciously democratic organization as all dues-paying members vote for the nine members of the Board of Directors (formerly the Executive Committee), each of whom serves a two-year term. In general this board establishes the political agenda and makes policy decisions for the organization. At times the board will survey the membership to determine which issues should receive a high priority. Once policy is decided upon, an executive director and an assistant director are responsible for enacting it. As with many public interest groups, Common Cause in Michigan finds that involvement in and commitment to the organization varies in response to the political climate.
Common Cause in Michigan is considered one of the most active chapters in the country by the national organization. A committed and effective leadership, backed by over 10,000 dues-paying members, was able to secure passage of the Political Reform Act of 1975 in Michigan. This omnibus act required candidates to file details of campaign finances, established a means of public financing for gubernatorial elections, and set standards for such financing, government ethics, and lobbying. After this act was struck down as unconstitutional by the Michigan Supreme Court in 1976, Common Cause in Michigan attempted to secure the piecemeal passage of the individual elements of the omnibus act. They have met with some success on the campaign financing, but have been thwarted on the less clearly defined issues of lobbying and ethics.
The records of Common Cause in Michigan comprise nearly seventeen linear feet of materials and consist of agendas, minutes, newsletters, correspondence, memoranda, press releases, reports, and drafts and comments on pending legislation. The materials document this public interest group's efforts to secure a more ethical, open, responsive, and representative government in Michigan. The strengths of the record group derive from its reflection of the reform issues salient to the Michigan electorate and the perspective it manifests on the close relations between the Michigan legislature and lobbyists in the 1970s, 80s and 90s. The records also shed light on the internal workings and outreach efforts of Common Cause in Michigan. The record group is arranged into three series: Administration, Office Reference, and Reforms. Each series is further divided by period of time (with overlap) reflecting the different dates of accessioning.
Subjects:
Elections--Michigan.; Lobbying.; Michigan--Politics and government--1971-1980.; Michigan--Politics and government--1981-1990.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-; Political action committees.; Political ethics.; Social action--Michigan--Societies, etc.
- Administration
  The Administration series (2 linear ft.; 1971-1984 and 1983-1998) consists of those records related to the internal operations and the outreach functions of the organization. The records are arranged alphabetically by type of material and by the group creating the records. The minutes of the Executive Committee and the Political Action Committee provide the best entry to the policy and decision-making processes of Common Cause in Michigan. The general correspondence and financial statements are also illuminating of the inner workings of the group. The Michigan newsletters and the press statements are quite informative and seem effective at communicating the leaders' message to the public at large.
  - 1971-1984
    - Executive Committee minutes and agenda, 1973-1983; 10 folders (Box 1)
    - Financial statements, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
    - General correspondence, 1974-1976; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Membership Reviews, 1973-1981 (Box 1)
    - Michigan Newsletters, 1971-1982; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Political Action Committee minutes and agenda, 1974-1981; 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Press statements, 1973-1977; 1982-1983; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - 1983-1998
    - Board Meetings, 1993-1998; 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Board Candidates, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Bylaws (Box 6)
    - Corporate Welfare Project Reports, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence-Holcomb-Merrill, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
    - Executive Committee Meetings-Agendas and Minutes, 1985-1989; 4 folders (Box 6)
    - Executive Committee Board Meetings-Agendas and Minutes, January-July 1994 (Box 6)
    - Executive Committee Meetings-Agendas and Minutes, August-December 1994 (Box 6)
    - Follow the Dollar Reports, 1998 (Box 6)
    - Member Analysis, 1988-1997 (Box 6)
    - Monthly Board Updates, 1993-1998 (Box 6)
    - Newsletters, 1983-1991 (Box 6)
    - Newsletters, 1992-1999 (Box 6)
    - Press Release, October 1986 (Box 6)
    - Project Manual (Box 6)
- Office Reference Files
  The Office Reference series (11.5 linear ft.; 1973-1982 and 1975-1998) consists of two basic kinds of files. Those files for 1973-1982 were created in the course of short term research projects undertaken by Common Cause in Michigan. The most extensive and most interesting of these records detail the Michigan legislature's campaign financing, dealings with lobbyists, and stands on Common Cause issues. The 1973 legislative survey polls the legislators on their positions on open meetings, campaign financing, lobbying disclosure and conflicts of interest. The legislator reports of the next few years assessed legislators' voting records on Common Cause issues and their response to requests for disclosure of campaign financing. Both the survey and the reports attempted to document every Michigan legislator. The Political Action Committee research project of the late 1970s altered the focal point of inquiry, turning attention to the influence wielded by two lobbyists, Francis Coomes and James Karoub. These reference files have been shaped by and reflect the larger reform goals of Common Cause in Michigan. The files for 1975-1998 included, in addition to research project files, collected background information on issues of concern to Common Cause.
  - 1973-1982
    - Bottle Bill, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Campaigns, 1974-1982; 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Constitutional Convention, 1978 (Box 2)
    - Franking privilege in Michigan, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Judicial reform, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
    - Legislative agents listing, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - Legislative reform, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - Legislative survey, 1973
      - General material (Box 2)
      - House Democrats (Box 2)
      - House Republicans (Box 2)
      - Senate Democrats (Box 2)
      - Senate Republicans (Box 2)
    - Legislator reports, 1974-1976; 19 folders (Box 2)
      arranged by Congressional district
    - Political Action Committee Research, 1977-1981
      - Basics, 1978-1980 (Box 3)
      - Bills, issues, and legislation, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
      - Campaign contributions, 1977-1979 (Box 3)
      - Construction industry, 1979-1980 (Box 3)
      - Francis Coomes lobbying, 1978-1980
        - PAC contributions (Box 3)
        - House committees (Box 3)
        - Senate committees (Box 3)
        - Joint committees (Box 3)
      - James Karoub lobbying, 1978-1980
        - PAC contributions (Box 3)
        - House committees (Box 3)
        - Senate committees (Box 3)
        - Joint committees (Box 3)
      - Right to Lobby (Francis Pletz), 1978-1981 (Box 3)
    - Survey of Public Interest Group Involvement (Constance Cook), 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Tax Reform survey, 1974-1976 (Box 3)
    - Tax Reform (seeking limitation), 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - 1975-1998
    - Absentee Ballots, HB 5529, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Accountability: State Legislators, 1988-1990 (Box 7)
    - Accountability Task Force, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Administrative Rules Court Case, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Augenstein Case: Lobbyists and Bribes, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
    - Balanced Budget Clippings, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Ballot Access-Michigan, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
    - Biennial Budget, 1993 (Box 7)
    - Bills Introduced, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
    - Bills Introduced and Bills Passed, 1995 (Box 7)
    - Bingo Ballot Proposal, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Campaign Disclosure Ruling, 1996 (Box 7)
    - Campaign Contributions in Wayne County, 1993-1994 (Box 7)
    - Campaign Finance, 1985-2000
      - Arthurhultz, 1992 (Box 7)
      - Arthurhultz, 1993 (Box 7)
      - Bills and Analysis, 1987-1989 (Box 7)
      - Bingo Changes, 1993-1996 (Box 7)
      - CC/MI Positions, 1997 (Box 7)
      - Campaign Finance Amendments, PA 95, 1989 (Box 7)
      - Campaign Finance Studies, Other States., 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Casino Contributions, 1985-1997 (Box 7)
      - Chamber vs. Secretary of State (SOS), Supreme Court, 1988-1990 (Box 7)
      - Check-off Campaign, 1988-1997 (Box 7)
      - Clippings, 1988 (Box 7)
      - Clippings, 1989 (Box 7)
      - Clippings, 1990; 2 folders (Box 7)
      - Clippings, 1991 (Box 7)
      - Clippings, 1992 (Box 7)
    - Campaign Finance, 1985-2000
      - Clippings, 1992-1995; 3 folders (Box 8)
      - Coleman Young Complaint, 1993 (Box 8)
      - Computerization, 1990-1992 (Box 8)
      - Corporate Participation, 1977-1987; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Council on Governmental Ethics Law-'A Model Law' (Box 8)
      - Enforcement Clippings, 1977-1982 (Box 8)
      - Enforcement, 1985-1989 (Box 8)
      - Ethics Commission, 1991-1995 (Box 8)
      - Gubernatorial Funding, 1993 (Box 8)
      - HB 4875 (Box 8)
      - Implementation, 1975-1981 (Box 8)
      - Independent Expenditures, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
      - Judicial Contributions, 1993 (Box 8)
      - Judicial Races, 1976-1989 (Box 8)
      - Laws and Rules, 1996-2000 (Box 8)
      - Michigan State Chamber of Congress, vs. Secretary of State (SOS), 1985-1986; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Michigan State Campaign Fund Booklet, 1997 (Box 8)
      - Office-holder Expense Fund, 1977-1987 (Box 8)
      - Office-holder Expense Fund, 1988 (Box 8)
      - Office-holder Expense Fund (OEF) Interpretive Statement, 1986 (Box 8)
      - Office-holder Expense Fund (OEF) Legislation, 1990-1991 (Box 9)
      - Office-holder Expense Fund (OEF) Rules, 1987-1989 (Box 9)
      - PA 388 of 1976, 1986 Amendment (Box 9)
      - Political Action Committee (PAC) Studies Released, 1982-1986 (Box 9)
      - Pollack Proposals, SB 799, 1993 (Box 9)
      - Public Funding (Box 9)
      - Secretary of State (SOS) Complaint/Caucus Information, 1982-1989; 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Statistical Report, 1984 (Box 9)
      - Task Force, 1989-1993 (Box 9)
    - Campaigns, 1988-1998
      - Check-off Campaign Public Relations Plan, 1998 (Box 9)
      - Senate, 1994 (Box 9)
      - Voter Campaign, 1988-1990 (Box 9)
    - Caucus Committees, 1995 (Box 9)
    - Clean Campaign Bill, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Conflict of Interest, 1968-1995
      - Clippings, 1973-1995 (Box 9)
      - Current Michigan Law, 1968-1980 (Box 9)
      - Congressional Campaign, 1992 (Box 9)
    - Constitutional Convention, 1978-1993
      - Clippings, 1978-1985; 5 folders (Box 9)
      - Clippings, November 1985-December 1985 (Box 10)
      - Clippings, 1993 (Box 10)
      - State of Michigan, Clippings, 1994 (Box 10)
      - Legislators Positions, 1982-1985 (Box 10)
      - Testimony on Senate Joint Resolution (JR), 1984 (Box 10)
      - Other Groups-Politicians, 1968-1979 (Box 10)
      - Other Groups-Politicians, 1981-1985; 3 folders (Box 10)
      - Senate Joint Resolution Amendment(S JR A), 1982-1989; 3 folders (Box 10)
      - Senate Joint Resolution Amendment (S JR A), Other Groups Opinions, 1983-1985; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Council of State Governments, 1989-1995 (Box 10)
    - Detroit Ethics, 1994-1995 (Box 10)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, Michigan, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
    - Ethics, 1974-1997
      - Bills Passed, 1993-1996; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Clippings, 1990-1995; 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Senator Brown, Expulsion from Senate, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
      - House Fiscal Agency, 1993-1995 (Box 10)
      - Indiana Information, 1990 (Box 10)
      - Josephson Institute, Oakland County Democrats, 1991 (Box 10)
      - Legislative Ethics, 1975-1997 (Box 10)
      - Laws-Other States-General Information (Box 10)
      - Laws-Other States-California, Indiana, Iowa, Louisiana, Missouri, Ohio, Oklahoma, Wisconsin. (Box 11)
      - Campaign Finance Complaints Against Warren Committee of the Future, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Campaign Finance Complaints Against Warren Mayor Bonkowski, 1993 (Box 11)
      - Legislative Ethics Commission, 1975-1994; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Local Issues, 1984-1998 (Box 11)
      - Policies, 1995 (Box 11)
      - Questionnaire, 1991 (Box 11)
      - Senator Mack, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
      - Senator Nelson, Dog Race Lobby Loan, 1978 (Box 11)
      - State Ethics Abuses, 1988-1993 (Box 11)
      - State Government, Laws, 1988 (Box 11)
      - Executive Branch Accountability, 1975 (Box 11)
    - Financial Disclosure, 1981-1991
      - General Information, 1981-1991 (Box 11)
      - Forms, 1990 (Box 11)
      - Forms-Samples. (Box 11)
      - Forms-Michigan Study with Sample Forms (Box 11)
      - Legislation in Other States (Box 11)
    - Freedom of Information Act (FOIA), 1976-1996
      - General Information, 1976-1994 (Box 11)
      - Enhanced Access, Computers, 1996 (Box 11)
      - Judge Kaza, 1994-1996 (Box 11)
      - Strategic Fund Board, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Governor's Race, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Gubernatorial Public Funding Report, 1976 (Box 11)
    - Gubernatorial Public Funding Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 11)
    - Guide to Democratic Party Soft Money Donors, 1996 (Box 11)
    - Honoraria, 1987-1990
      - General Information, 1987-1990 (Box 11)
      - Travel and Lodging, 1988-1991 (Box 11)
      - Travel and Interpretive Statement, 1989-1991 (Box 11)
    - Incumbents, 1974-1990 (Box 11)
    - Independent Candidates, 1974-1988 (Box 11)
    - Inheritance Tax, 1990 (Box 11)
    - Insurance Regulation, 1978-1990 (Box 11)
    - Judicial Commission, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Judicial Qualifications Commission, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Judicial Races, 1984-1992 (Box 12)
    - Lawsuit Sealing Settlements, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
    - League of Women Voters, Gubernatorial Public Funding Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 12)
    - Legislative Funds, 1977-1990 (Box 12)
    - Legislative Oversight, 1989 (Box 12)
    - Legislative Pay, 1990-1993 (Box 12)
    - Legislative Pay Increases, 1992-1996; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Legislative Pay/Perks, 1982-1993 (Box 12)
    - Legislative Pay, State Officers Compensation Commission (SOCC), 1993 (Box 12)
    - Legislative Questionnaire, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Legislator Rankings, 1988-1992 (Box 12)
    - Lobby Bills, Representative Kaza, 1996-1997 (Box 12)
    - Lobby Law, 1982-1993
      - Clippings, 1982-1993 (Box 12)
      - Rules, 1979-1981 (Box 12)
      - Interview between Lou Gordon and Lobbyist James Karoub. (Box 12)
      - Revisions, 1984-1986 (Box 12)
    - Lobbyist Study in Arizona, 1991 (Box 12)
    - Merit Selection of Judges, 1973-1992; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Michigan Coalition to Stop MX Missile, 1988-1990 (Box 12)
    - Michigan's State Elections, Overview, 2000 (Box 12)
    - Municipal Ethics:, 1974-1994
      - General Information, 1974-1983 (Box 12)
      - Clippings, 1988-1994; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - None of the Above (NOTA) Ballot Option, Representative Kaza, 1995 (Box 12)
    - Officeholder Expense Funds (EOF) Legislation, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Open Meetings:, 1976-1994
      - Act of 1976 and Attorney General Opinions, 1977, 1976-1977 (Box 12)
      - Clippings, 1977-1996 (Box 12)
      - Court Case, 1988-1992 (Box 12)
      - Court Case, 1993-1994 (Box 12)
      - House Bill (HB) 5415, 1988-1989 (Box 12)
      - Implementation Clippings, 1976-1983 (Box 12)
      - Passage, Clippings, 1972-1976 (Box 13)
      - Proposed Amendments, 1977-1985 (Box 13)
      - State Laws, 1976-1981 (Box 13)
    - Political Action Committee (PAC) Brochure, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Political Action Committees (PAC) Influence on State Campaigns, 1986-1988 (Box 13)
    - Political Action Committee (PAC) Listing, 1985 (Box 13)
    - Political Action Committee (PAC) Listing, 1988 (Box 13)
    - Political Action Committee (PAC) Project Manual, 1982 (Box 13)
    - Political Action Committee (PAC) Studies:, 1982-1993
      - Campaign Contributions, Released, 1986 (Box 13)
      - Contributions, Released, 1992 (Box 13)
      - Fundraising, Released, 1989 (Box 13)
      - "Left Over" Study, Released, 1990 (Box 13)
      - Legislative Fundraising, Released, 1991 (Box 13)
      - Lobbyist Contributions, 1988-1992 (Box 13)
      - Orders to Secretary of State (SOS), 1989-1993 (Box 13)
      - Post General Analysis, Released, 1988 (Box 13)
      - Study Summaries, 1982-1988 (Box 13)
    - Part-time Lawmakers, Clippings, 1985-1993 (Box 13)
    - Petitions for Senators, Originals, 1975-1977 (Box 13)
    - Political Party Bingo, Clippings, 1987 (Box 13)
    - Presidential Primary Legislation, Clippings, 1977-1992 (Box 13)
    - Presidential Search at University of Michigan, Clippings, 1980-1995; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Privacy Act, House Bill (HB) 4812 and House Bill (HB) 5100, 1987-1989 (Box 13)
    - Public Financing:, 1980-1990
      - General Information, 1980-1990; 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Campaign Legislation, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
      - Proposals, New Jersey, 1988 (Box 13)
      - State Elections, 1989 (Box 13)
      - State Elections Data Book, 1986 (Box 13)
      - State Legislation, 1976-1990; 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Other States, 1988 (Box 13)
      - Public Service Commission, 1980-1982 (Box 13)
    - Reapportionment:, 1977-1990
      - Apportionment Commission, 1981 (Box 13)
      - Chamber Proposal, 1977-1984 (Box 13)
      - Clippings, 1990-1991 (Box 13)
      - Common Cause (CC) Model, 1975-1981 (Box 13)
      - Common Cause (CC) Report, 1977 (Box 13)
      - Court Case, 1989-1990 (Box 14)
      - District Lists by Zip Code, 1980-1983 (Box 14)
      - General Information, 1978-1988 (Box 14)
      - Legislative Maps, 1972; 1975 (Box 14)
      - Michigan Supreme Court Case, 1982 (Box 14)
      - Task Force, 1972-1982 (Box 14)
    - Reapportionment in the States, 1982-1994 (Box 14)
    - Records Media Act, 1989-1990 (Box 14)
    - Records Retention Legislation, 1985-1988 (Box 14)
    - Redistricting:, 1982-1991
      - General Information, 1991 (Box 14)
      - Michigan, 1982 (Box 14)
    - Redistricting Contest:, 1985-1992
      - Additional Pages (Box 14)
      - Census/Racial Data, 1990 (Box 14)
      - Additional Racial/Population Data, 1990 (Box 14)
      - Counties/Population Information, 1990 (Box 14)
      - Entries (Box 14)
      - Entry Forms, 1991 (Box 14)
      - General Information, 1985-1992 (Box 14)
      - Maps/Census Tract Information, 1990 (Box 14)
      - Original Kit, 1991 (Box 14)
      - Requests for Additional Information (Box 14)
    - Redlining, 1977-1979 (Box 14)
    - Revolving Door: Banking Commission, House Bill (HB) 4854, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Revolving Door Clippings, 1978-1993 (Box 14)
    - Right to Know, 1983-1985 (Box 14)
    - South Africa Divestment, 1981-1988 (Box 14)
    - State Board of Canvassers, July 1994 (Box 14)
    - State Board of Canvassers, August-September 1994 (Box 15)
    - State Campaign Clippings, 1986 (Box 15)
    - State Campaign Clippings, 1988 (Box 15)
    - State Campaign Clippings, 1990 (Box 15)
    - State Campaign Fund: Public Relations Campaign, 1998 (Box 15)
    - State Contracts, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Statistical Reports:
      - Candidate, Independent, Political and Ballot Question Committees, 1986 (Box 15)
      - Reports, 1986-1994; 5 folders (Box 15)
      - Analysis, 1986-1988 (Box 15)
    - Sunset (Bill), 1976-1983
      - Clippings, 1976-1989; 5 folders (Box 15)
      - Clippings, Backlash, 1976-1981 (Box 15)
      - Common Cause (CC) Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 15)
      - Legislative Comments, 1978-1979 (Box 15)
      - Legislative Program Effectiveness Review, 1977 (Box 15)
      - Other States, Colorado, 1978 (Box 15)
      - Other States, General, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
      - Other States, Texas, 1979-1981 (Box 15)
      - Performance Audit, 1981-1984 (Box 15)
      - Research Council Report, 1976-1983 (Box 15)
      - Senate Bill (SB) 75 Testimony, 1979 (Box 15)
      - Taxes: State Issues, 1983 (Box 15)
    - Term Limits:, 1977-1992
      - Formation of Michigan Citizens Against Term Limitation, 1992 (Box 15)
      - General, 1977-1992; 3 folders (Box 15)
      - General, 1993-1995 (Box 16)
    - 'Takings' Legislation-Property Rights Preservation Act, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Tax Expenditure Task Force, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Tax Issues: Common Cause (CC) Positions, 1976-1986 (Box 16)
    - Unicameral Legislation, 1981-1994 (Box 16)
    - Voter Registration:, 1977-1995
      - Act, 1993-1995; 4 folders (Box 16)
      - Amendments, 1989 (Box 16)
      - Background, 1983-1989 (Box 16)
      - By Mail, 1977-1995 (Box 16)
      - Elections, House Bill (HB) 4961-HB 4963 (Box 16)
      - General Information, 1988-1992 (Box 16)
      - Homeless, 1993 (Box 16)
      - Legislation, 1985-1988 (Box 16)
      - Other States, 1984-1985 (Box 16)
      - Special Advisory Committee, 1995 (Box 16)
      - Task Force, 1989-1993; 5 folders (Box 16)
      - Technology, 1990-1991 (Box 16)
    - Water Quality/Quantity, 1984 (Box 16)
    - Whistleblower's Protection Act, 1981-1993 (Box 16)
- Reforms